Guide to the Richard Brown Baker Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Richard Brown Baker papers
1895-2004
YCAL MSS 691
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
91.79
(108 boxes)
The Richard Brown Baker Papers consist of correspondence; art and artist files; professional and personal papers; exhibit files; diaries; writings; photographic prints, negatives, and slides; photograph albums; objects; printed material; and an audiocassette interview.
Baker, Richard Brown
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Richard Brown Baker to Yale University Art Gallery, 2003 and 2007.
Custodial History
Transferred from Yale University Art Gallery to Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 2003 and 2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 108 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Richard Brown Baker (1912-2002)
Richard Brown Baker was born in Providence, RI on November 5, 1912. He attended the Moses Brown School in Providence, RI before attending Yale University, from which he graduated in 1935. Following Yale, he was awarded a Rhodes Scholarship and received a BA and MA from Oxford University's Honour School of Philosophy, Politics and Economics. After school, Richard's varied career commenced. His first job, in 1939, was as a reporter and editorial assistant for the Providence Journal, a post he occupied only briefly before he accepted the position of private secretary for Ambassador Alexander Weddell and his wife Virginia Weddell in Madrid, Spain in January 1940. He returned to the United States at the end of 1940 and in 1941 was a Social Science Analyst at the Library of Congress. From there he moved to the Office of Strategic Services and worked in Washington, London, and Paris as a Research Analyst. His last employer was the Central Intelligence Agency as a Foreign Affairs Officer. He quit in 1948 to focus on developing his career as a writer.
Baker's writing career was brief but he did publish two works in 1952: a book of poetry entitled Stairways to Another Stage and a book based on the diary he kept while in London during 1944, entitled The Year of the Buzz Bomb. His books were not the success that he hoped for and he decided to focus on modern art, moving to New York City in 1952 to begin painting. He briefly studied with the painters Hans Hoffman and Morris Kantor, but then turned his energy toward collecting art.
Baker's career as an art collector suited him very well. He became a famous art collector, owning over 1,600 works of art before he died. He focused almost exclusively on young emerging artists and was often the first collector to purchase works from artists who became famous, such as Roy Lichtenstein and Jackson Pollock. He lent works of art from his collection to museums and galleries throughout the world, enabling many exhibitions of new works. He was an avid traveler and he documented his international trips in his diaries and letters to family. He did on January 22, 2002 in Shelburne, VT.
Scope and Contents
The Richard Brown Baker Papers consist of correspondence; art and artist files; professional and personal papers, including papers relating to the Baker family and Baker's childhood; exhibit files; diaries; writings; photographic prints, negatives, and slides; photograph albums; objects; printed material; and an audiocassette interview.
Arrangement
Organized into four groupings: I. September 2003 Acquisition, 1895-1998. II. March 2004 Acquisition, 1959-2004. III. December 2006 Acquisition, 1941-2004. IV. June 2007 Acquisition, 1953-2002.
Art -- Collectors and collecting -- United States; Art, American -- 20th Century; Artists -- United States; Audiovisual materials; Diaries; Exhibition catalogs; Film negatives; Photograph albums; Photographic prints; Slides (photographs); Sound recordings; Baker, Richard Brown
- September 2003 Acquisition, 1895-1998; 1; 62.79; (78 boxes)
  Arrangement
  This material is organized into sixteen series: Correspondence; Art Files; Exhibit Files; Writings; Yale Diaries; Diaries; Early Writings; Foreign Service Material; Other Writings; Baker Family Papers; Material Relating to Baker's Youth; Bound Diaries; Other Papers; Photographs and Photograph Albums; Objects; and Printed Material.
  Scope and Contents
  Formerly Uncat MSS 598.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 108 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Correspondence
    Contains correspondence between Baker and galleries, museums, friends, and family.
    Organized into two subseries: Galleries and Museums; and Other Correspondents.
    - Galleries and Museums
      - Addison Gallery of Art, 1964 (Box 1)
      - Akademie Der Kunste, 1974 (Box 1)
      - Akron Art Institute, 1966-1983 (Box 1)
      - Alexander and Alexander, 1978 (Box 1)
      - Albany Knox Art Gallery, 1960-1990 (Box 1)
      - Aldrich Museum of Contemporary Art, 1965; 2 (Box 1)
      - Alternative Museum, 1983-1994 (Box 1)
      - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1980-1990 (Box 1)
      - American Crafts Museum, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
      - American Federation of Arts, 1959; 4 (Box 1)
      - American Museum in Britain, 1973-1991 (Box 1)
      - Amherst College, 1971 (Box 1)
      - Stedelijk Museum, Amsterdam, 1977-1982 (Box 1)
      - Apartment Art Tours, 1967-1973 (Box 1)
      - Archives of Art in America, 1960-1969; 3 (Box 1)
      - Art in America, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
      - Art Institute of Chicago, 1959-1972 (Box 1)
      - Art Collectors Club of America, 1956-1971 (Box 1)
      - Art Commission of the City of New York, 1977-1979; 2 (Box 1)
      - Art Dealers Association of America, 1978-1993 (Box 1)
      - Artco Management, International, 1974-1976 (Box 1)
      - Arthur, John, 1991 (Box 1)
      - Arts and Science Center, 1978 (Box 1)
      - Arts Club of Chicago, 1960-1972 (Box 1)
      - Arts Council of Great Britain, 1968-1977 (Box 1)
      - The Asia Society, 1970-1975 (Box 1)
      - Attingham Park, the Shropshire Adult College, 1963-1992 (Box 1)
      - Association for the Advancement of American Art, 1966-1969 (Box 1)
      - Australia Council, 1976 (Box 1)
      - Baden-Baden Staatliche Kunsthalle, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
      - Baltimore Gallery of Art, 1973, 1976 (Box 2)
      - Bard College, 1988-1990 (Box 2)
      - Bennington College, 1961 (Box 2)
      - Boston Arts Festival, 1959 (Box 2)
      - Boston Atheneum, 1981-1987 (Box 2)
      - Boston Institute of Contemporary Art, 1962-1983 (Box 2)
      - Boston Museum of Fine Art, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
      - Brandeis University: Rose Art Museum, 1983-1991 (Box 2)
      - New York State University Art Gallery, Binghamton, 1977 (Box 2)
      - Museum of Art, Science and Industry, Bridgeport, Connecticut, 1965 (Box 2)
      - British Council, 1964-1966 (Box 2)
      - Brooklyn College of the City University of New York: Art Department, 1977 (Box 2)
      - Brooks Memorial Art Gallery, 1965-1984 (Box 2)
      - Brown University Department of Art, 1972-1992 (Box 2)
      - Bucknell Center Gallery, 1982 (Box 2)
      - Burchfield Center: Western New York Forum for American Art, Buffalo State University College, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
      - Castle Gallery: College of New Rochelle, 1986 (Box 2)
      - Carnegie Institute, 1955-1962 (Box 2)
      - Center for Inter-American Relations, 1969-1972 (Box 2)
      - Century Association, 1996 (Box 2)
      - Chicago Museum of Contemporary Art, 1968-1978 (Box 2)
      - Centro Cultural Arte Contemporano, 1986 (Box 2)
      - Child Study Association, 1968, 1969 (Box 2)
      - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1966-1987 (Box 2)
      - College of New Rochelle, 1987 April 28 (Box 2)
      - Columbia University International Associates for Contemporary Art, 1986-1989 (Box 2)
      - Contemporary Arts Center Cincinnati, 1963-1995 (Box 2)
      - Contemporary Arts Museum Houston, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
      - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1956-1981 (Box 2)
      - Corpus Christi Museum of South Texas, 1973, 1974 (Box 2)
      - Crocker Art Gallery Association, 1973, 1985 (Box 2)
      - Dallas Museum for Contemporary Arts, 1961-1973 (Box 2)
      - Darmstadt, Eine Ausstellung, 1970 (Box 2)
      - Dartmouth College, 1962-1980 (Box 2)
      - Dayton Art Institute, 1956 February 2 (Box 2)
      - Delaware Art Center of Wilmington, 1967, 1971 (Box 2)
      - De Cordova Museum, 1973-1975 (Box 2)
      - Denver Art Museum, 1956-1989 (Box 2)
      - Des Moines Art Center, 1962-1987 (Box 2)
      - Detroit Institute of Art, 1966 (Box 2)
      - Documenta, 1972-1977 (Box 2)
      - Dresden: Staatliche Kunstsammlugen, 1991 (Box 2)
      - Drew University, 1959-1962 (Box 2)
      - Elvehjem Museum of Art, 1993 November 22 (Box 2)
      - Everson Museum of Art, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
      - Ewald, Elin Lake, 1997 (Box 2)
      - Finch College Museum of Art, 1965-1974 (Box 2)
      - Fine Arts Federation of New York, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
      - Fine Arts Work Center in Provincetown, 1978 January 11 (Box 2)
      - Fine Arts Gallery of San Diego, 1974-1987 (Box 2)
      - Fogg Art Museum, 1963 June 18 (Box 2)
      - Florida State University Gallery, 1959 January 2 (Box 2)
      - Fort Lauderdale Museum of Art, 1986-1997 (Box 2)
      - Fort Wayne Museum of Art, 1978 October 30 (Box 2)
      - Frankfurt Stadelsches Kunstinstitut und Stadtisch Galerie, 1982 (Box 2)
      - Fashion Institute of Technology, 1984 (Box 2)
      - Allen Frumkin Gallery, Inc., 1974 (Box 2)
      - Fundacio Antoni Tapies, 1993 (Box 2)
      - Gallery of Modern Art, 1965 (Box 2)
      - Goddard Riverside Community Center, 1969 (Box 2)
      - Grolier Club, 1971, 1978 (Box 2)
      - Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, 1956-1994; 4 (Box 2)
      - Harold Reed Gallery, 1984 January 31 (Box 2)
      - Haus der Kunst Munchen E.V., 1981-1982 (Box 2)
      - Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, 1973-1992 (Box 2)
      - Honolulu Academy of Arts, 1977, 1978 (Box 2)
      - Heckscher Museum, 1992 (Box 2)
      - Hyatt, Gordon, 1991 April 8 (Box 2)
      - Institute of International Education, 1968 (Box 2)
      - Institute on Art Collection, 1972 March 1 (Box 2)
      - Institute of Contemporary Art, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
      - Ivam Centre, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
      - Jewish Museum, 1963-1966 (Box 2)
      - John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art, 1961-1981 (Box 2)
      - Joslyn Art Museum, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
      - Katonah Gallery, 1969-1980 (Box 3)
      - Krannert Art Museum, 1961,1974 (Box 3)
      - La Jolla Museum of Contemporary Art, 1974 (Box 3)
      - Lehigh University, Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, 1979 (Box 3)
      - Städtisches museum leverkusen schloss morsbroich, 1968 (Box 3)
      - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1964-1984 (Box 3)
      - Louisiana Museum of Modern Art, 1975 (Box 3)
      - Musee des Arts Decoratifs, Palais du Louvre, 1960 (Box 3)
      - Museum Ludwig, 1988-1992 (Box 3)
      - Madison Art Center, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
      - Marquette University, 1981 (Box 3)
      - Marion Koogler McNay Art Institute, 1959 January 23 (Box 3)
      - Miami Art Center, 1974 (Box 3)
      - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1959-1983 (Box 3)
      - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1967-1985; 2 (Box 3)
      - Middlebury College, 1993, 1994 (Box 3)
      - Milwaukee Art Center, 1968-1980 (Box 3)
      - Minneapolis Institute of Arts, 1959-1964 (Box 3)
      - Mississippi Museum of Art, 1996 (Box 3)
      - Montgomery Museum of Fine Arts, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
      - Moore College of Art, 1979 (Box 3)
      - Moses Brown School, 1995 (Box 3)
      - Moravian College, 1983 (Box 3)
      - Morgan and Brother Manhattan Storage, 1969-1985 (Box 3)
      - Mount Holyoke College Friends of Art, 1974 September 24 (Box 3)
      - Municipal Art Society, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
      - Munson-Williams Institution, Museum of Art, 1963 (Box 3)
      - Museum Images Inc., 1991 (Box 3)
      - Museum of Contemporary Art Los Angeles, 1982-1989 (Box 3)
      - Museum of Contemporary Hispanic Art (Mocha), 1986 (Box 3)
      - Museum of Fine Arts Houston, 1958, 1959 (Box 3)
      - Museum of Modern Art, New York, 1955-1993; 6 (Box 3)
      - Nancy Hoffman Gallery, 1995 February 28 (Box 3)
      - National Collection of Fine Art, Smithsonian Institution, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
      - National Gallery of Art, Washington, 1978-1990 (Box 3)
      - National Gallery of Canada, 1958-1968 (Box 3)
      - Nassau County Museum of Fine Art, 1981-1994 (Box 3)
      - New Museum, New York, 1979 (Box 3)
      - Neuberger Museum, 1978-1987 (Box 3)
      - New Jersey Center for Visual Arts, 1993 (Box 3)
      - Newark Public Library, 1965-1969, 1997 (Box 3)
      - Newark Museum, 1956-1978; 2 (Box 3)
      - New Britain Museum of American Art, 1989 (Box 3)
      - New Jersey State Museum, 1966-1970 (Box 3)
      - New York State Exposition, 1965 (Box 3)
      - New York Studio School, 1984-1988 (Box 3)
      - Newport Harbor Art Museum, 1977-1984 (Box 3)
      - North Carolina Museum of Art, 1957-1969 (Box 3)
      - North Virginia Community College, 1976 January 19 (Box 3)
      - Oakland Museum, California, 1977 April 25 (Box 3)
      - Oakland University, Meadow Brook Art Gallery, 1966-1994; 6 (Box 3)
      - Orlando Museum of Art, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
      - Musee nationale d'art moderne, Paris, 1982 (Box 4)
      - Pasadena Art Museum, 1958-1971 (Box 4)
      - Pamela Auchincloss Gallery, New York, 1991 (Box 4)
      - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 1972-1975 (Box 4)
      - Philadelphia College of Art, 1976-1982 (Box 4)
      - Phoenix Art Museum, 1973 (Box 4)
      - Portland Art Museum, Oregon, 1982-1985 (Box 4)
      - Pratt Institute, 1976 (Box 4)
      - Princeton University Art Museum, 1967 (Box 4)
      - Public Education Association, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
      - Queensboro Community College Art Gallery, 1992 (Box 4)
      - Radcliffe Collectors' Exhibition, 1974 (Box 4)
      - Radcliffe Club of New York, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
      - Reiland, Lowell, 1989 (Box 4)
      - Renwick Gallery, 1976 (Box 4)
      - Rhode Island School of Design, 1957-1996; 15 (Box 4)
      - Roberson Center for the Arts and Sciences, 1987 (Box 5)
      - Robert McLaughlin Gallery, Ontario, 1974-1977 (Box 5)
      - Rochester Memorial Art Gallery of the University of Rochester, 1957-1974 (Box 5)
      - Rosc. International Art Exhibit, Dublin, 1972 (Box 5)
      - Rose Art Museum, Brandeis University, 1968-1984 (Box 5)
      - Rothmans of Pall Mall Canada, 1975 (Box 5)
      - Rotterdam, Museum Boymens-van Beuningen, 1970 (Box 5)
      - Royal Academy of Arts, 1990-1991 (Box 5)
      - Santa Barbara Museum of Art, 1981 (Box 5)
      - City Art Museum, Saint Louis, 1969 (Box 5)
      - Saint Mary's College, Notre Dame, Indiana, 1969 (Box 5)
      - Museum of Fine Arts, Saint Petersburg, Florida, 1975-1976 (Box 5)
      - San Antonio Museum Association, 1980-1982 (Box 5)
      - San Francisco museum of art, 1973-1974; 2 (Box 5)
      - Sculpture Center, 1991 (Box 5)
      - Setagaya Art Museum, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
      - Shippensburg University of Pennsylvania, 1981-1990 (Box 5)
      - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, 1988 March 1 (Box 5)
      - Smith College Museum of Art, 1958-1968 (Box 5)
      - Southeastern Center for Contemporary Art, 1990 (Box 5)
      - Squibb Gallery, 1979 (Box 5)
      - Stamford Museum, 1976-1981 (Box 5)
      - University Art Gallery, State University of New York, Albany, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
      - Staten Island Institute of Arts and Sciences, 1956-1970 (Box 5)
      - Sterling and Francine Clark Art Institute, 1976, 1977 (Box 5)
      - Studio Museum in Harlem, 1967-1979 (Box 5)
      - Tampa Bay Art Center, 1976-1980 (Box 5)
      - Tampa Museum, 1980-1987 (Box 5)
      - Tate Gallery, 1975-1992 (Box 5)
      - Tel Aviv Museum, 1977 (Box 5)
      - Toledo Museum of Art, 1957-1975 (Box 5)
      - Art Gallery of Toronto, 1966-1984 (Box 5)
      - Tetryakov Museum, Moscow, 1990 (Box 5)
      - Union College, New Jersey, 1979 (Box 5)
      - United States Mission to the United Nations, 1966 (Box 5)
      - University of California, Berkely, 1968-1985 (Box 5)
      - University of California at Los Angeles, 1963-1964 (Box 5)
      - University of California, Santa Barbara, 1975-1976 (Box 5)
      - University of Georgia, 1982-1984 (Box 5)
      - University of Illinois at Chicago, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
      - University of Kansas Museum of Art, 1972 June 20 (Box 5)
      - University of Maryland, 1979 (Box 5)
      - University of Notre Dame Art Gallery, 1968-1969; 2 (Box 5)
      - University of Pennsylvania, 1986 October 1 (Box 5)
      - University of Rhode Island, 1964-1992 (Box 5)
      - University of South Florida, 1966-1969; 2 (Box 6)
      - University of Texas at Austin, 1964, 1968 (Box 6)
      - University of Vermont, 1981-1984 (Box 6)
      - University of Wisconsin, 1967 (Box 6)
      - Visitor Comments, 1957-1993; 5 (Box 6)
      - Valparaiso University Art Galleries, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
      - Vancouver Art Gallery, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
      - Visual Arts Museum, New York, 1961, 1976 (Box 6)
      - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1962-1975 (Box 6)
      - Walker Art Center, 1958-1983; 2 (Box 6)
      - Washington Gallery of Art, 1963 (Box 6)
      - Wellesley College, 1962-1963, 1991 (Box 6)
      - Wesleyan University, 1964, 1994 (Box 6)
      - Wilkes College, 1982 January 8 (Box 6)
      - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1955-1997; 4 (Box 6)
      - Wichita Art Museum, 1976 (Box 6)
      - Wichita State University, 1975-1990 (Box 6)
      - William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art, 1967, 1984 (Box 6)
      - Wolverhampton Art Gallery and Museums, 1985 (Box 6)
      - Wurttembergischer Kunstuerein Stuttgart, 1972-1974 (Box 6)
      - Yale Center for British Art, 1986-1991 (Box 6)
      - Yale University Art Gallery, 1955-1989; 18 (Box 7)
      - Yale University Art Gallery, 1991-1996; 5 (Box 8)
    - Other Correspondents
      - Busadee, Jamlong, 1971-1988 (Box 8)
      - Caroline, 1992 (Box 8)
        Includes photographs
      - "B-C" general, 1954-1991; 4 (Box 8)
      - Field, Virginia, 1955-1994; 4 (Box 8)
        Includes photographs and postcards.
      - Rubin, Harold, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
      - Correspondence, 1946-1994; 3 (Box 8)
      - Moses Brown School, 1983-1994 (Box 8)
      - "Paul", 1971 (Box 8)
        Includes two book plates.
      - Family correspondence, 1957-1973; 24 (Box 9)
  - "Art Files"
    Contains exhibit catalogues, pamphlets, postcards, clippings, correspondence, writing drafts, photographs, slides, negatives, transparencies, loan agreements, appraisals, and art books.
    - Avenue and Art News, magazines, 1978, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Studio International, magazine, 1965 January (Box 10)
    - Art International, magazine, 1961 September 20 (Box 10)
    - Harvey Baker Fellowship, clipping, 1966 March (Box 10)
    - Exhibit catalog, Baker collection at Yale University, 1975 (Box 10)
    - Clippings, correspondence about Baker's collection, 1978-1996 (Box 10)
    - Architectural League, correspondence and photographs, 1995 October (Box 10)
    - Photographs, 1995 February (Box 10)
      Photographs taken of Baker, his collection and friends in his apartment.
    - Photograph of Baker and Bruce Herland, 1991 (Box 10)
    - Inventory of Baker's collection
    - Gallery invoices, bills pertaining to Baker's collection, 1958-1990; 4 (Box 10)
    - Art Exhibits based on the Baker collection, undated (Box 10)
    - "Mid Century Paintings, Collages, Drawings and Sculptures in the collection of Richard Brown Baker," typescript, undated (Box 10)
    - Copies of catalog cards describing Baker's collection of artwork, undated; 2 (Box 10)
    - Inventory of Baker's collection, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Accession of Baker's art collection, reproduction, undated (Box 10)
    - "Drawings (including collages, gouaches and water colors) in the collection of Richard Brown Baker...," list, 1981 August 26 (Box 10)
    - Invoices, purchases for Baker's art collection, 1950-1960 (Box 10)
    - Accession of Baker's art collection, list, 1973 May (Box 10)
    - Baker's art inventory, 1985 December 17 (Box 10)
    - Writings about artists, typescripts, 1959-1962 (Box 10)
      Baker's notes on artists and works of art. Includes, Roy Lichtenstein, Franz Klein's Wannamaker Block, James Rosenquist, Lucas Samaras, Robert Indiana, Hans Hoffman, Pollack's Arabesque, Roger Brown's Presidential Commemorative.
    - Exhibit catalogs, 1959-1992; 16 (Box 11)
    - Exhibit catalogs, 1964-1995 (Box 11)
    - Exhibit catalogs, 1995 (Box 11)
    - Paintings drawings and sculpture collected by Yale Alumni, 1960 (Box 11)
    - Research material, 1964-1985; 4 (Box 11)
      Includes photographs, loose clippings, correspondence about shows, artists, or individual works owned by Baker.
    - Research material, 1993-1996; 17 (Box 12)
    - Research material, 1992-1996; 16 (Box 13)
    - Research material, 1991-1997; 12 (Box 14)
    - Research material, 1959-1997; 16 (Box 15)
    - Research material, 1990-1991; 17 (Box 16)
      Includes clippings, announcements, post cards
    - Clippings, 1960-1992; 20 (Box 17)
      Loose clippings, photographs, correspondence about shows, artists, or individual works owned by Baker.
  - "Exhibit Files"
    Contains correspondence with curators, diary excerpts, installation photographs, catalogs, publicity, and reviews on exhibitions of Baker's collection of contemporary art.
    - Rhode Island School of Design, 1959 (Box 18)
    - Staten Island Museum, 1960 (Box 18)
    - Drew University, 1960, 1962; 2 (Box 18)
    - Walker Art Center, 1960-1961 (Box 18)
    - Wellesley College, 1963 (Box 18)
    - Yale University Art Gallery, 1963 (Box 18)
    - Museum of Modern Art "Visits to private collectors,", 1964 (Box 18)
    - Rhode Island School of Design, 1964 (Box 18)
    - University of Rhode Island, 1964 (Box 18)
    - Larry Aldrich Museum, 1965 (Box 18)
    - Oakland University (Michigan), 1967 (Box 18)
    - University of Wisconsin, 1967 (Box 18)
    - University of South Florida, 1967 (Box 18)
    - Baker, photo album, 1967-1970 (Box 18)
      The paintings and works of art collected by Baker on view in his Park Avenue apartment.
    - XIX Olympiad, Mexico City, 1968 (Box 18)
    - University of South Florida, 1969 (Box 18)
    - University of Notre Dame, 1969 (Box 18)
    - Yale University, Alumni Collecting, 1960 (Box 18)
    - Yale University Art Gallery, 1971-1972 (Box 18)
    - San Francisco Museum of Art, 1973 (Box 18)
    - Rhode Island School of Design, 1973; 2 (Box 18)
    - Oakland University (Michigan), 1974 (Box 18)
    - Rhode Island School of Design, 1973-1985; 4 (Box 18)
    - Yale University Art Gallery, 1975 (Box 18)
    - Newark Museum, 1974-1975 (Box 18)
    - American Federation of Art, 1975-1977 (Box 18)
    - Stamford Museum, 1978 (Box 18)
    - Squibb Gallery, 1979; 2 (Box 19)
    - Oakland University (Michigan), 1979-1980 (Box 19)
    - Katonah Gallery, 1980 (Box 19)
    - Century Association, 1980 (Box 19)
    - Rochester School of Design, "Fortissimo!", 1981-1985; 2 (Box 19)
    - Portland Museum of Art (Oregon), "Fortissimo!", 1985 (Box 19)
    - San Diego Museum of Art, "Fortissimo!", 1982-1985 (Box 19)
    - Tatistcheff and Company, 1995 (Box 19)
    - Oakland University, "Expressive Visions", 1991 (Box 19)
    - Frumkin/Adams Gallery, 1992 (Box 19)
    - Century Association, "Works by Younger Artists", 1993 (Box 19)
    - Yale University Art Gallery, 1985-1996; 6 (Box 19)
  - Writings
    - Diaries
    - "My summer in Hitler's Germany," typescript, 1934 (Box 20)
    - "Frau Professor," typescript, 1941 (Box 20)
    - Typescript, p. 18-150, 1944 June-1945 January 7 (Box 20)
    - Diaries, typescript, 1952-1960 (Box 20)